In this lecture, we are going to discuss about another AWS AI service in the area of natural
language processing called as Amazon Comprehend.
Amazon Comprehend derives and understands valuable insights from
text and the text could be informed documents, email, or web pages.
Now let's try and understand how Amazon Comprehend works.
So, you have Amazon Comprehend, then as an input, you could have social media feed or your emails,
call center records, etc.
Amazon Comprehend can analyze the data on these different data sources and then generate insights.
Now, let's try and understand what generating insight means.
So, the first one is it can detect PII, let's say you are an insurer and one of the customers
has posted a complaint on your social media channel, let's say Instagram or Facebook saying that
this is the policy number name address and it has certain complaint against the organization.
So, what Amazon Comprehend can do is it can review that data feed and detect any PII information.
Then it can also do sentiment analysis, let's say you launched a new product in the market
and you are getting a lot of feedback, it can be on social media or it can be,
it can be complaints that are coming to your call center or emails.
So, Amazon Comprehend can generate the sentiment analysis on all the feedback that you are getting
and it can classify it as positive neutral or negative.
So, the third focus area for Amazon Comprehend is recognize entities or entity recognition.
So, let's say there is some chatter going on in our social media feed.
Amazon Comprehend can then do the entity recognition and recognize the objects within the field
and classify them into some predefined categories like name of the person,
name of the organization that is being spoken about, location and so on.
Then it can also detect key phrases from data and key phrases basically identifies
the central idea of a particular post or email etc that has been sent.
And it can also auto detect the language of the content.
So, now let's see what are the key use cases for Amazon Comprehend.
So, it can be used for call center analytics, customer support tickets and it could do various
things, it could detect PII, it could do sentiment analysis, recognize entities, key phrases, etc.
Then it can be also used to secure documents by redacting the PII from documents where it is not
required. So, I said you could get an email with a complaint and which provides all the PII
information or somebody could post on social media feedback with the PII data and it can be used
to redirect the PII from documents. And then it could also be used for processing the financial
documents by classifying and extracting entities from insurance claims.
So, those are some of the use cases for Amazon Comprehend.